Welcome back everyone. Today Pat and I will be reviewing an online session you played with pretty high stakes.
皆さん、お帰りなさい。今日はパットと一緒に、かなりハイステークスでプレイされたオンラインセッションをレビューします。
What do you have for us here, brother?
何を用意してくれましたか？
Table 1 is $150 on GG. Table 2 is a $2k/$4k big game. Table 3 is a $215 MTT. Then a $1k Thrill, a $630, and a $54.
テーブル1はGGの$150です。テーブル2は$2k/$4kのビッグゲーム。テーブル3は$215のMTT。そして$1k Thrill、$630、$54です。
Cool. Let's jump in. Immediately we see you playing a big pot with AQ. Remember the action?
いいですね。早速見ていきましょう。すぐにAQで大きなポットをプレイしています。アクションを覚えていますか？
Pre-flop we open 2BB, he 3-bets to 10BB.
プリフロップは2BBオープンし、相手が10BBに3-betしました。
What do you think pre-flop? What does your red dot mean?
プリフロップはどう思いますか？その赤いドットは何を意味していますか？
It marks a 'red line' player. I think the decision is easy versus a red line guy. Clear call. I'd fold versus nits.
「レッドライン」プレイヤーという意味です。レッドラインの相手に対しては判断が簡単です。明確なコールですね。ニット相手ならフォールドします。
For those watching, 2BB to 10BB against general population is an easy fold. But against a good aggressive reg?
視聴者の皆さんのために言うと、一般的なプレイヤー相手に2BBから10BBは簡単なフォールドです。しかし、優秀でアグレッシブなレギュラー相手なら？
A red line player has a high win rate without showdown. They are aggressive and have appropriate bluffs.
レッドライン・プレイヤーはショーダウンなしの勝率が高いです。彼らはアグレッシブで、適切なブラフを持っています。
Good point. So they make it 10BB, you call. Pot size indicates they c-bet a quarter and you called?
いい指摘です。彼らが10BBにし、あなたはコール。ポットサイズから見て、彼らは1/4ポットのc-betをし、あなたはコールしましたか？
Yeah, c-bet a quarter. Decision on the turn now. What do you think about turn with AQ?
はい、1/4のc-betでした。ターンの決断です。AQでのターンについてどう思いますか？
One of the worst hands we land with. Opponent plays Kx this way, but also plays hands that beat us that might fold now or later.
ここで持っているハンドの中では最悪の部類に入ります。相手はKxをこのようにプレイしますが、フォールドしうる、私たちに勝っているハンドも持っています。
I'm torn on whether to bluff. Lean towards bluffing?
ブラフするかどうか迷っています。ブラフ寄りですか？
If you're torn, it's close. If you lean bluff every time, you aren't losing much EV.
迷うということは、僅差だということです。毎回ブラフ寄りだとしても、EVの損失は大きくないでしょう。
Here, it's important not to block hands like QQ♥️ calling turn and folding river, rather than blocking flushes.
ここでは、フラッシュをブロックするよりも、ターンをコールしてリバーでフォールドするQQ♥️のようなハンドをブロックしないことが重要です。
AQ without a ♥️ becomes a good triple barrel.
♥️のないAQは、トリプルバレルに適したハンドになります。
Tough. I have QJs. Don't have AJo pre. Most bluffs will be AQ, 65s, 54s. Struggling for bluffs.
難しいですね。QJsはあります。プリフロップでAJoはありません。ブラフのほとんどはAQ、65s、54sになるでしょう。ブラフを探すのに苦労しています。
We have 15 combos of AQ bluffs. We have TT for value. Probably play AA this way too. Just thinking if we are over-bluffing.
AQのブラフコンボは15通りあります。バリューのためのTTもあります。AAも恐らくこのようにプレイするでしょう。オーバーブラフになっていないか考えています。
Yeah, that's a big point. Sometimes it's the best option to overbluff.
ええ、それは重要なポイントですね。オーバーブラフが最善の選択になることもあります。
I 100% agree. If you're in this spot, always shove AA here versus almost anyone when they make it 10bb.
100%同意します。このスポットで相手が10bbにしてきたら、誰が相手でもAAなら常にオールインすべきです。
The solver might slow play, but don't do it. Just always shove AA, always shove KK.
ソルバーはスロープレイするかもしれませんが、それはしないでください。AAやKKは常にオールインしましょう。
When the option's close, and bluffing small is really good, just always take that bluffing small option.
判断が際どくて、小さくブラフするのが有効な時は、常にその小さなブラフを選びましょう。
We don't need to bet big to get AT♠️ or JJ without a ♥️ to fold.
AT♠️や♥️のないJJをフォールドさせるのに、大きくベットする必要はありません。
Yeah, and I think there is a ton of EV in betting turn.
ええ、turnでベットすることには多くのEVがあると思います。
I think the turn is mandatory because of the Tx and the JJ with no heart.
TxやハートのないJJがあるため、turnのベットは必須だと思います。
But then the question is: do we follow through or not?
しかし問題は、その後も攻め続けるかどうかです。
Looks like you're going third and not quarter? You rewound the hand.
クォーターではなくサード（1/3）を打ったようですね？ハンドを巻き戻しましたね。
Yeah, I wanted to get the earliest street. I went 8.5bb.
はい、一番最初のストリートを見たかったんです。8.5bbを打ちました。
So 8.5bb is going to be a mandatory call versus most players.
8.5bbは、ほとんどのプレイヤーに対して必須のコールになります。
Checking who he is might not change my pre-flop decision with AQ, but it sets my mindset for the hand.
相手が誰かを確認してもAQでのプリフロップの判断は変わらないかもしれませんが、ハンド全体の考え方を決めることになります。
He went third instead of quarter, which makes sense based on the smaller pre-flop raise.
彼もクォーターではなくサードを打ちましたが、プリフロップのレイズが小さかったことを考えると理にかなっています。
But I don't think it changes our decision tree. We still call flop and bet turn.
しかし、デシジョンツリーが変わるとは思いません。flopをコールし、turnをベットするハンドであることに変わりはありません。
It's just information for later. It doesn't change the decision immediately.
それは後のための情報であって、直ち判断を変えるものではありません。
I wouldn't like betting turn then giving up river. Either bet turn and follow through, or check turn.
turnでベットしてriverで諦めるのは好きじゃありません。turnを打って貫き通すか、チェックするかです。
Oh, you don't like shutting down?
ああ、途中で止めるのは好きじゃないんですね？
I never shut down. Once he checks twice, you get good bluffing opportunities.
絶対止めませんね。相手が2回チェックしたら、絶好のブラフの機会が得られます。
The more a range checks, the more likely it is to fold.
レンジがチェックすればするほど、フォールドする可能性は高くなります。
When he bets flop and checks twice, 99 is always in that range.
相手がflopを打って2回チェックした場合、99は常にそのレンジに含まれます。
When we bet turn, that range still has AA and AK.
私たちがturnを打つ時、そのレンジにはまだAAやAKが含まれています。
You strip the strong hands when he double checks.
相手がダブルチェックした時点で、強いハンドは除外されます。
It's important to point out that 99 are not in this range for a lot of players.
多くのプレイヤーにとって、99はこのレンジに含まれていないことを指摘するのは重要です。
Neither is ATs, neither is AJ.
ATsも、AJも含まれていません。
A strong argument can be made for folding against players who are massively under 3-bet.
3ベットの頻度が極端に低いプレイヤーに対しては、フォールドすべきという強い議論が成り立ちます。
And the speed of the 3-bet. When playing 6 tables, I really watch timing.
3ベットのスピードも重要です。6面打ちしている時は、タイミングをよく見ています。
If he has A5s, he thinks 'do I flat or 3-bet?'. If he has AK, he just 3-bets.
A5sなら「フラットか3ベットか」悩みますが、AKならすぐに3ベットします。
We ran into AK, which doesn't say much about my bluff really.
AKにぶつかりましたが、私のブラフについてはあまり語っていません。
It only says a lot if he calls with AT♠️.
もし彼がAT♠️でコールしてきたら、私のブラフについて多くを語ることになりますが。
So you limp AA, 100bb deep on table 1. Let's talk about limping theory.
テーブル1で100bbディープでAAをリンプしましたね。リンプの理論について話しましょう。
From a GTO perspective, it wants more limps at 100bb deep stack depth.
GTOの観点からは、100bbのディープスタックでは、より多くのリンプが推奨されます。
...the positional disadvantage, that's again from a theoretical perspective,
……ポジションの不利、これは理論的な観点ですが、
against weaker opponents who are going to overfold post-flop.
ポストフロップでオーバーフォールドする弱い相手に対しての話です。
I'm a big, big fan of having a very high SB raise, just 'cause I think they play so bad.
私は SB から非常に大きくレイズするのが大好きです。彼らはあまりに下手だと思うからです。
I think people overfold to it, they overfold flop, therefore you're profiting a lot.
彼らはそれにオーバーフォールドし、フロップでも降りすぎるので、大きな利益になります。
You also don't get limp 3-bet bluffed by an average guy.
それに平均的な相手からリンプ 3-bet ブラフを受けることもありません。
They don't limp 76s and then 3-bet.
彼らは 76s でリンプして 3-bet はしませんから。
I'll take that raising, I'm doing the SB.
そのレイズ戦略を採用します。私が SB だとして。
Oh from the SB? Yeah, yeah, sure.
あ、SB からですか？ええ、もちろん。
Well, it works both ways, like people are too passive in position and out of position.
インポジションでもアウトオブポジションでも、人々はパッシブすぎるので両方機能します。
Just do something aggressive blind versus blind and it's going to work well.
ブラインド対ブラインド（BvB）でアグレッシブに動けばうまくいきますよ。
And this is actually the spot you're talking about when you're in the BB and SB limps...
これはあなたが BB にいて SB がリンプした時の状況についてですが……
...is actually something Chrissy recently talked about where like in early stages at really deep stacks, if the SB limps,
最近 Chrissy が話していたことですが、序盤のディープスタックで SB がリンプした場合、
she just raises and doesn't really care if she gets called because of the fold frequency post-flop is high enough...
彼女はコールされるか気にせずレイズします。ポストフロップのフォールド頻度が高いので……
...that like she's just winning a bigger pot on average.
……平均してより大きなポットを獲得できるからです。
And so attacking like the capped range, those weaker ranges that limp-call...
キャップされたレンジや、リンプコールする弱いレンジを攻撃することは……
...when people are unbalanced is just going to turn a really nice profit.
……相手がアンバランスな場合、非常に良い利益を生みます。
So back to the decision at hand, what sizing do you like here and why?
では決定の話に戻りますが、ここではどのサイジングを好みますか？
Well I think when I'm playing a $150 tournament, there's two things that I ask myself straight away:
150ドルのトーナメントなら、すぐに2つのことを自問します。
Who is the opponent and what does my hand want to do?
ヴィランは誰か、そして自分のハンドは何をしたいのか？
Who is the opponent? What does my hand want to do? AA wants to get lots of money in pre-flop.
ヴィランは誰か？ハンドは何をしたいか？AA はプリフロップで多くのお金を入れたがっています。
So what's the best way to do that?
では、そのための最善の方法は？
Um, in general, if I'm limping AA, it's versus someone that is going to do the Chrissy B thing, right?
一般的に AA でリンプするのは、Chrissy B のような戦略をとる相手に対してです。
That's going to raise 85o 100% frequency.
85o を100%の頻度でレイズしてくるような相手です。
That way, like they're going to put 3.5 bigs in and then we want to check-raise to really big sizing.
そうすれば相手は 3.5bb 入れてくるので、そこで非常に大きくチェックレイズしたいのです。
Cause we want to now get... 85o is going to fold whatever, but we want to get the maximum versus JTs or whatever.
なぜなら……85o はどうせフォールドしますが、JTs などに対して最大利益を得たいからです。
Versus a range that wants to see a flop, you want to charge that range a lot of money cause it's not going to 4-bet.
フロップを見たがっているレンジに対しては、高く請求したいのです。相手は 4-bet しないので。
He's never going to 4-bet a bluff here, he's just going to see a flop.
彼はここでブラフ 4-bet はせず、ただフロップを見ようとします。
So in those instances it's very good to go big with value.
そういう場合はバリューのために大きく打つのがとても有効です。
When your range is kind of polarized, the other person is incentivized to call.
こちらのレンジがポラライズされていると、相手はコールしたくなります。
That's... when your polarity increases, your sizing generally wants to increase with it...
ポラリティが高まるにつれ、サイジングも大きくしたいのです……
...cause you're not interested in seeing a flop, if that makes sense. So really nice big check-raise sizing.
……フロップを見ることには興味がないからです。だからナイスなビッグ・チェックレイズですね。
The absolute smallest I think we should go here is like 13 to 14.
ここで絶対的に最小のサイズは 13〜14bb くらいだと思います。
I could definitely see logic for going larger.
もっと大きくする論理も十分わかります。
I think I went 15... I gave the AA discount.
私は 15bb にしたと思います……AA 割引を与えました。
You gotta just give him a little bit of rope keeping in.
相手をつなぎ止めるために少し余裕を与えないといけません。
That's why I thought about 13 or 14 cause you have that AA discount because like, yeah, you're looking for action.
だから私も 13 か 14 を考えました。アクションが欲しいので AA 割引ですね。
13.9 or something, 13.99 for a little discount.
13.9 とか、13.99 とか、少しディスカウントして。
Yeah, I'm in for it.
ええ、賛成です。
Let's see what I do. I go... okay, I go pretty big. I go big and chunky.
私がどうしたか見てみましょう。あー……かなり大きく行きましたね。ガッツリと。
But yeah, just always asking myself, who is the villain and what does my hand want to do?
でも常に自問しています、ヴィランは誰で、ハンドは何をしたいのか？
So if it's a passive guy, I would just raise 7x there because he's not going to 3-bet me...
パッシブな相手なら、単に 7x レイズします。3-bet してこないでしょうし……
...and he's going to call JTs whatever I do. So just target the inelastic continues kind of.
……私が何をしても JTs でコールするでしょうから。非弾力的なコンティニューを狙います。
If you go 3.5x with AA, that's kind of the only money that's going in there unless he has JJ, TT, QQ.
AA で 3.5x にすると、相手が JJ、TT、QQ を持っていない限り、入るお金はそれだけです。
They 3-bet if you go 7 anyway, so you're just guaranteeing money gets in there.
7x でもそれらのハンドは 3-bet してくるので、確実にお金が入るようにするだけです。
Yeah, definitely.
ええ、間違いありません。
Um, now let's talk about table three. We're UTG, jams 8-handed for 7bb.
ではテーブル3について話しましょう。UTG で 8人テーブル、7bb オールインです。
We have ATs. What are your like thought process here?
ハンドは ATs です。ここでの思考プロセスは？
Um, who is villain and what does my hand want to do?
ヴィランは誰か、ハンドは何をしたいか？ ここはフォールドしたいですね。
I think I just want to fold here.
このレンジにはこちらがドミネートしているハンドがあまり含まれていません。
Um, this range shouldn't have many hands that we dominate in it.
A9o がレイズフォールドする可能性がありますが、それくらいです。後ろに5人いますし。
As in A9o can raise-fold, that's the only one. And there's 5 stacks behind.
ええ、でも A9o はレイズフォールドし得るとして、実際するか、それともショブしてくるか？
Yeah, but like, A9o could raise-fold, but will it raise-fold or will it just shove?
AJ、AK、AQ は常にショブしてきます……こちらがドミネートされています。
AJ, AK, AQ always shove... they dominate.
ええ。ただ、弱い Ax コンボをここで過剰にショブするプレイヤー層が……
Yeah. I would say that like there is a certain percentage of the population who just jams way too many of their weak Ax combos here...
……一定数いて、7bb に対して広すぎるレンジで突っ込んできます。だから相手が誰かが重要です。
...and is just jamming too wide for 7. And so, you know, who is my opponent is naturally a very good first question.
でも、これは非常に際どい（クロースな）状況だと思います。
But I think this one's extremely close.
ひとつ言えるのは、もし状況が際どくて、私が 30bb 持っていて……
One thing, if it's close, like let's say I have 30bb here and I can call-fold to everyone behind.
……後ろ全員に対してコールフォールドできるなら別ですが、スタックの3分の1を失うのは痛手ですよね？
I don't know.
分かりません。
So 9 off the money, I think better to just... if I'm not sure, just put zero in.
インマネくまで9人なら、確信がなければ0にしておくのがいいでしょう。
Oh, 9 off the money? See, that's an incredibly important factor.
えっ、インマネまで9人？それはめちゃくちゃ重要な要素ですね。
You're 18 off the money. 79 left, 61 pay. It makes it significantly closer when there's this much ICM.
インマネまで18人ですね。残り79人で61人入賞。ICMがこれだけあると判断が難しくなります。
Players are going to shove tighter, chips in our stack are much more valuable than they are otherwise.
プレイヤーのシャブはタイトになり、チップの価値は通常より遥かに高くなります。
So what if you're in the first 40% of a tournament?
じゃあトーナメントの序盤40%ならどうします？
Oh, we gambling. We getting our gambling shoes on.
それならギャンブルですね。ギャンブルモード全開で。
Your range is strong enough here where you probably don't want to have that many call folds. You're not looking to VPIP tons of hands here.
ここのレンジは十分強いので、コールフォールドは減らしたいですね。VPIPを上げすぎる場面ではありません。
So you have enough traps in your calling range that you're comfortable calling. Maybe if we flat here, AQ hero folds?
コールレンジに十分なトラップがあるので、快適にコールできます。ここでフラットしたらAQはヒーローフォールドするかな？
Yeah, I think call is better as well. But it is worth noting that if someone jams the CO and you have ATs on the BTN, it's going to be a re-jam.
ええ、コールの方がいいですね。ただ、COがジャムしてBTNでATsを持っていたら、リジャムになる点は重要です。
For sure. But then you don't have five guys behind that can wake up with TT or JJ.
ですね。でも後ろにTTやJJを持っているプレイヤーが5人もいるわけじゃありません。
Just a close spot, I'll keep my 20 BBs and operate. I'd prefer to do that.
微妙なスポットなので、20BB温存して立ち回ります。その方が好みですね。
So, assuming you fold. Are you gonna fold? You can just tell us and we can go to the other hand here.
フォールドと仮定して。フォールドします？教えてください。
I thought I'd keep the suspense. No, I just fold, yeah.
サスペンスを持たせようかと思って。はい、フォールドします。
So I'm going to go back to this Q5♥️ hand.
では、このQ5♥️のハンドに戻りましょう。
MP opens, SB calls, we overcall Q5s.
MPオープン、SBコール、Q5sでオーバーコール。
It comes nothing for us. The turn is an A♥️ after it checks through. And what are your thoughts on leading versus checking?
フロップはスカ。チェックで回ってターンはA♥️。ドンクとチェック、どう思います？
I think a lot of people will just think like 'Oh I have a flush draw I have to lead'.
多くの人は「フラッシュドローがあるからドンクしなきゃ」と考えるでしょうね。
I don't see much fold equity here. The way Q5 makes its EV is once in position checks back and says I don't have QJ or KJ, I have 66.
フォールドエクイティはあまりないですね。Q5がEVを出すのは、インポジションがチェックバックして「QJやKJはない、66だ」と言う時です。
At the moment I'm attacking two ranges that still have Jx.
現状、まだJxを持っている2つのレンジを攻撃していることになります。
If I check the turn, I can hit my flush or I can bluff with more info. Delaying this hand till the river makes a lot of sense.
ターンをチェックすれば、フラッシュを引けるか、より多くの情報でブラフできます。リバーまで待つのは理にかなっています。
Yeah, and I do think it's a spot where people make the mistake of just leading turn because they have equity. I don't think you're gonna get folds often enough.
ええ、エクイティがあるからとターンでドンクするミスをしがちです。十分なフォールドは得られないでしょう。
It comes back to that thing: what does my hand want to do? Q5 wants to see a river for really good bluffing spots and it wants to realize.
結局、自分のハンドが何をしたいかです。Q5は良いブラフスポットのためにリバーを見たいし、実現したいんです。
Have I called the river here? You did call the river here.
リバーでコールしましたっけ？はい、コールしましたよ。
I didn't see him value betting 88... And I thought a Jack would bet the turn really often.
88でバリューベットするとは思えませんでした…ジャックならターンで打つことが多いですし。
So sometimes we lose to J9s, J8s, JTs. But there's K-highs, 98s. There's enough bluffs in there I think.
J9s、J8s、JTsには負けますが、Kハイや98sもあります。十分なブラフが含まれていると思います。
I was actually really just surprised to see his exact hand. He showed you a full house bro.
相手のハンドを見て本当に驚きました。フルハウスが出てきましたよ。
If he value bet 99, well played. I just wouldn't expect it.
99でバリューベットしたならナイスプレイです。予想外でした。
But we saved the whole stack mate, we saved 4 BBs back.
でもスタックは守れましたよ。4BB温存できました。
Do you think people have the mental aspect of 'well my hand could have bet the turn so it's okay if I lose a bet anyway'?
「どうせターンで打てたハンドだし、1ベット失ってもいいや」とメンタル的に正当化すると思いますか？
No, I think people have the mental aspect of they need to win the pot rather than make the maximum EV decision.
いいえ、最大EVの決断より、ポットを勝ちたいというメンタルがあるんだと思います。
You checking the turn there will make more money for Q5♥️ but you'll lose the pot more often. It's a very strange paradox.
ターンでチェックすればQ5♥️の利益は増えますが、ポットを落とす頻度も上がります。奇妙なパラドックスですね。
I can just call the river.
リバーはコールだけでいいですね。
There is definitely some logic to it. I kind of thought that way before.
確かに理にかなっています。僕も以前はそう考えていました。
I could see people making that mistake where, let's say 66 checks back...
そのミスをするのも分かります。例えば 66 がチェックバックしたとして……
...and someone leads the river. They think 'I would've lost if I c-bet anyway, so I can call 66.'
……相手がリバーでドンクを打ってきたら、「どうせ c-bet しても負けていただろうからコールできる」と考えます。
But with 66, you're not putting the right amount of money in the pot, so it can't be that bad.
でも 66 ではハンドに見合った額をポットに入れていないので、それほど悪くはないはずです。
If you were meant to lose this bet, it can't be too bad, I think.
このベットで負ける運命だったなら、それほど悪くはないと思います。
But that's the mental issue. We mentally trick ourselves into making mistakes.
でも、それがメンタルの問題です。自分を騙してミスをさせてしまうんです。
So you defend J6o here versus UTG+1?
では、ここで UTG+1 に対して J6o をディフェンスするんですか？
Yeah. I think the vast majority of people are just gonna fold this pre-flop.
ええ。たぶん大半の人はプリフロップでフォールドすると思います。
All charts are 2.2x or 2.3x at 36BB. None of them are min-raise.
どのチャートも 36BB では 2.2x か 2.3x です。ミニレイズはありません。
Also, something happens with the 6 because most of his range is Ace high.
それに 6 があると何か起きますよね。相手のレンジの大半は A ハイですから。
With the 6, hands like K6s flat 4-bets because of the 2-3-4-5 effect.
6 があると、2-3-4-5 効果のおかげで K6s のようなハンドで 4-bet にフラットできます。
I'd fold J5o and call J6o. But it's very marginal.
J5o はフォールドして J6o はコールします。でも非常にマージナルです。
Fair enough. Playing 6 tables, I take any small edge. At 10 tables, I fold this.
なるほど。6面打ちなら小さなエッジも拾いますが、10面打ちならフォールドします。
That's an easy spot to miss with K8o. That's a pure call for 4BB.
ところで、K8o は見落としやすいスポットです。4BB ならピュアコールです。
I don't know about that. What's the stack depth there?
それはどうかな。スタックの深さは？
Why is this a pure call? I would always fold this.
なぜピュアコールなんですか？ 僕ならいつもフォールドします。
Run it in HRC. I used to fold too, but with money in the SB getting 3 to 1...
HRCで計算してみてください。僕も以前は降りてましたが、SBにお金が入っていて3対1のオッズなら……
Sometimes the original raiser shoves and it gets heads up.
オリジナルレイザーがオールインしてヘッズアップになることもあります。
Also with 4BB, I'm looking for any reason to gamble.
それにここで 4BB しかなければ、ギャンブルする理由を探します。
I can't reach the prize pool, I don't cover anyone. In PSKOs, you want to gamble when short.
賞金圏外で誰もカバーしていない。PSKOでショートの時はできるだけギャンブルすべきです。
Keep in mind, your decision would change if registration wasn't still open.
レジストレーションがまだ開いていなければ、判断は変わることを覚えておいてください。
Not gonna lie, in a $55 game I'm more incentivized to gamble than in a 10k.
正直、1万ドルの試合より55ドルの試合の方がギャンブルしたくなりますね。
The truth comes out. It's still a call. You should call way wider than people do.
本音が出ましたね。でも依然としてコールです。人が思うよりずっと広くコールすべきです。
At 4-5 BBs when covered, find any excuse to gamble or you make no money.
4-5BBで全員にカバーされているなら、ギャンブルする口実を探すべきです。そのままでは稼げません。
Table 4, you raised K10. BB is Joao, very good reg. What's your read?
テーブル4で K10 をレイズ、BB は Joao。優秀なレギュラーですが、どう読みますか？
Yeah, solid player. Very good.
ええ、堅実なタイプです。非常に良いプレイヤーですね。
I don't see him defending wide this deep. Are you balancing a wide c-bet range?
この深さで広くディフェンスするとは思えません。広い c-bet レンジをバランスさせているのですか？
Mostly small bets happen here. It's a flush draw board.
ここでは主にスモールベットが使われます。フラッシュドローボードですから。
He has good run outs around the 4 and 6, and a nut advantage.
4 や 6 周辺で彼に有利なランアウトが多く、ナットアドバンテージがあります。
He has K6o, K4o, 64o, and we don't. So not much big betting.
彼には K6o、K4o、64o がありますが、私たちにはありません。だからビッグベットは起きません。
Technically. But if he check-raises a quarter pot often, I'll bet half pot.
テクニカルにはそうです。でも 1/4 ポットで頻繁にチェックレイズされるならハーフポットを打ちます。
Who is the opponent? K10 wants action but has kicker problems.
相手は誰か、K10 はどうしたいか。アクションが欲しいですが、キッカーの問題があります。
Folding AK? Video frozen... Oh, you added two more tables.
AK をフォールド？ 動画が固まったのかな。あ、テーブルを2つ追加したんですね。
Yeah, it should go back to normal in a second. Okay, I can adjust the thing though. Hold on a sec.
ああ、すぐに元に戻るはずだ。OK、調整できるよ。ちょっと待って。
So we didn't see the size that he check-raised on the flop with, but I imagine it's like 4x or 5x?
彼が flop でチェックレイズしたサイズは見えなかったけど、たぶん4倍か5倍くらいかな？
It's pretty easy to figure out. You bet 1.4 into 5.6 and now there's 15.6, so he made it 5 big blinds.
計算は簡単だよ。5.6のポットに1.4を打って、合計15.6になったんだから、彼は5bbにレイズしたことになる。
So again, this really comes down to player type. When you bet 25% on the flop, most high stakes regs are going to do a lot of check-raising with 6x and 4x.
これもプレイヤーのタイプによるね。flop で25%のベットをすると、多くのハイステークスのレギュラー（reg）は6xや4xで頻繁にチェックレイズしてくる。
In a solver, those hands are always randomizing. It's very easy for a human to not randomize 65 and just check-raise versus 25%. So it's definitely an over-bluffed node.
ソルバーではそういうハンドは頻度を混ぜるけど、人間は65で25%ベットに対して毎回チェックレイズしてしまいがちだ。だから flop は間違いなくブラフ過多な状況だね。
And then, what do you think about the turn? Would you bet or check?
で、turn はどう思う？ ベットする？ それともチェック？
I think he is actually going to have a lot of flush draws as well facing the smaller sizing. He's also going to have 58, 78.
小さいサイズに対して、彼はフラッシュドローもたくさん持っていると思う。58や78も持っているだろうね。
But those gut-shots only have 6.6%, so it's not a big concern. I think if you go too much smaller, you might just get check-raised again.
でも gut-shot は勝率が6.6%しかないから、それほど心配ない。ベットが小さすぎると、またチェックレイズされる危険があるけどね。
I wouldn't mind... I think it's so unnatural for him to check value on the turn here. This is where you can actually make quite a lot of money waving the red flag.
僕は構わないと思う... ここで彼がバリューハンドでチェックするのは不自然すぎる。ここは弱みを見せて（waving red flag）稼げる場面だよ。
It's really tough for him to check-raise a flop with a 6 and then go for a double check-raise on the turn. You don't mind inducing here.
6を持って flop をチェックレイズした後、turn でもチェックレイズするのは難しい。ここでアクションを誘う（induce）のは悪くないよ。
You make a lot of money because it's easy for him to over-bluff. He's kind of repping exactly 44. If you trigger something, he's likely to just have a random 4x♣️ or 75.
彼がオーバーブラフしやすいから稼げるんだ。彼は44を主張しているようなものだけど、実際はランダムな4x♣️や75を持っている可能性の方が高い。
So he folds. Also going to go back to the AK at 42 effective. Let me get off this 4 wide screen.
彼はフォールドしたね。次は42bb持ちのAKのハンドに戻ろう。画面を調整するよ。
You'll notice the vast majority of people are just all-in for 40bb here with AK. And for most people, that's probably the best play.
ここでは大半の人がAKで40bbをオールインするし、多くの人にとってはそれがベストプレイだろう。
However, when you do have such an aggressive 4-betting and bluffing image, you get to click hands like this.
でも、アグレッシブな4ベットやブラフのイメージがあるなら、こういうハンドで小さくレイズ（click）するのもありだ。
This is 'Egyptian' the streamer. I've been coaching him for years. So he knows all about... he knows I might be light.
相手は「Egyptian」という配信者で、何年もコーチングしている生徒だ。だから僕がライトにプレイする可能性があると知っている。
There's definitely a non-zero percent chance he just takes A4s and he's just over it versus me here.
彼がA4sなどで、僕に対して無理やり突っ込んでくる可能性はゼロじゃない。
Also what it does do, the times it goes all-in, all-in, you can probably get away then.
それにこうすることで、全員がオールインしてきた時に逃げることができる。
As in if the UTG guy shoves, and now Pat shoves with a cold 4-bet range behind, this is AA and KK only. So you can get away.
もしUTGがショブして、後ろのPatもコールド4ベットでショブしてきたら、それはAAかKKだけだ。だからフォールドできる。
Yeah, I hadn't thought about that. Shove call, lose less, induce. Multi-faceted benefits here.
それは考えてなかったな。面白い。ショブをコールできるし、負けを減らせるし、誘うこともできる。メリットが多いね。
If he has AJo or A5s, I'm fine with those hands calling. If he starts having 78s, now it becomes dicey, now I'm more likely to shove.
彼がAJoやA5sならコールされても構わない。もし78sなどが出てくるなら危険だから、その時はショブする方がいい。
As the range gets more linear, you shove AK. And then as the range gets more polar you're facing, then you start clicking it. If he's calling AQ, I'm always shoving AK.
相手のレンジがリニアならAKはショブする。ポーラーなレンジなら小さく打つ（click）。彼がAQでコールしてくれるなら、僕は常にAKでショブするよ。
Yeah, for sure. All right, well let's end this part here, and we will see everyone in the next one.
そうだね。よし、このパートはここで終わろう。次は次の動画で。